

# ANIRUDDHA JANA

Datascience Enthusiast & Upcoming Software Developer

Kolkata, West Bengal, India

## **PROFILE**

I am a student studying ECE at VIT, Vellore. I have interest in learning more about Computer Vision, Machine Learning, IoT and software development & I want to enhance my knowledge in these fields through experience.

Python and C++ languages are the programming languages that I use most for making projects. Till now, I have participated in 6 hackathons, out of them I have won two.

Additionally, I am a quick learner, adaptable, and enjoy working collaboratively to achieve shared goals.

#### CONTACT

**PHONE:** 9007567361

LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/aniruddha-jana-aj/

**EMAIL:** aniruddhaj43@gmail.com

# **HOBBIES**

Watching Movies Cycling Playing sports and games Listening music

# **LANGUAGES**

English Hindi Bengali

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Winner of Social Impact track of HoyaHacks 2022
Winner of Sponsor track of WaffleHacks 2022

## **EDUCATION**

Kendriya Vidyalaya, Ballygunge (2013 – 2020)

Class X - 92.2%

Class XII - 94.8%

KVB U14 Football team player at Regional Level KVB U19 Football team player at Regional Level

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore (2020-2024)

ECE - Current CGPA - 9.05

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Chegg India [Chegg Subject Matter Expert]

May 2022 - March 2023

Freelance expert with the responsibility to provide quality answers to questions uploaded to their Q&A portal. Questions on the Chegg Q&A portal are uploaded by student subscribers from across the world.

• VITMAS [Technical Head]

Jan 2022 – Feb 2023

I had various responsibilities from planning technical events to organizing hackathons. Also, I was mentoring around 200 students in the technical domain of VITMAS, and out of them, I am mentoring around 80 students for educating them, inspiring them, and influencing them in Data Science and Electronics field.

• LetsGrowMore [Data Science Intern]

Jan 2022- Feb 2022

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

• Student Organizer of COGNITION hackathon

Aug 2022

SAS department of VIT, Vellore in collaboration with VITMAS

Event Coordinator of IDEATHON 4.0

Sep 2022

Official event in gravitas 2022, VIT Vellore

# **SKILLS**

- ✓ Quick Learner
- Positive attitude
- Strategic planning

- ✓ Leadership
- Flexibility in thinking
- ✓ Resolution skills

✓ Technical Skills-

Programming - Python, C++, Java, C, Embedded C

Machine Learning- Tensorflow, PyCaret, OpenCV, yoloV7 Web development- HTML5, CSS3, JS, Flask, Django, Streamlit

Query language- MySQL

Version Control- Git, GitHub

Hardware Simulation- MULTISIM, LTSPICE, Proteus

Fundamental coding concept- Data Structures and algorithms